Academic Affairs and Provost, Office of Senior V.P. for; Records ua500
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Office of the Senior Vice President For Academic Affairs And Provost Records
1845 - 2017 May 17
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
ua500
92.29 cubic ft.
51 captures
Includes the records of the Office of the Provost which oversees the academic mission of the University. Materials in this collection address all aspects of academic policy at the University: program planning and review, faculty policies and salary practices, grading policies, long-range planning, and budgeting.
Administrative History
The office of the Vice President for Academic Affairs was established in 1965 by President Evan R. Collins as a successor to the Office of the Dean, which had previously overseen academic programs. The Provost manages all aspects of the University's academic mission. This includes oversight of all of the undergraduate and graduate programs, enrollment, and advisement. The Provost is also responsible for overseeing the registration process for new academic programs as well as the periodic review, conducted by the State Education Department and by outside accrediting bodies, of existing programs. As of 2016, the office is referred to as the Office of the Provost, while the Provost's title remains Senior Vice President for Academic Affairs and Provost.
Scope and Contents
Includes correspondence and reports of the Vice President for Academic Affairs relating to the establishment, accreditation, and review of academic departments and programs; the closing of the Milne School and phasing out of particular academic programs in the 1970s; administrative policies about probation, transfer students, enrollment and faculty salaries; long range planning documentation; documents on international programs; and campus construction and space planning documentation. Also included is a complete run of bulletins and course catalogs.
Arrangement of the Collection
This collection is arranged into 8 series. Series 1 contains archived versions of the Provost's website. Series 2 through 6 contain materials designated by the State retention schedule for permanent retention: bulletins (Series 2), program registration letters from the State Education Department (Series 3), program accreditation letters from outside accrediting bodies (Series 4), articulation agreements (Series 5), and supporting materials documenting the program registration and review processes (series 6). Series 7 consists of curriculum development materials that document the approval of individual courses at the University. Series 8 contains administrative records from the Office of the Provost that document the day to day administrative functions of the Office. Finally, Series 9 contains materials related to the deactivation and/or discontinuation of academic programs from the years 2010-2018.
Acquisition Information
Items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives. Additional materials (particularly materials from Series 6: "Program Registration and Review Records" were accessioned from a records storage room overseen by the Office of the Provost in the Fall of 2016. 2016
Related Materials
Related collections in the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives can be found in the subject guide for Criminal Justice and Prisons.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Web Archives
Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted with the exception of series 6 and 7; these two series are partially processed and may contain personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.
Education, Higher--Administration.; Universities and colleges--Accreditation.; Accreditation (Education); Web Archives; Administrative records; Letters (correspondence); Memorandums; Wages -- New York (State); State University of New York at Albany. Office of the Provost; State University of New York at Albany. Office of the Vice President for Academic Affairs
- Website for the Office of the Provost, 2009 September 12 - 2017 May 17; 1; 51 captures
  URL
  http://www.albany.edu/academics/provost.shtml
  Access Requirements
  The item contains web archives preserved as WARC files. They must be access though web archival replay tools such as the "Wayback Machine." The links here direct you to files hosted by the Internet Archive, but you may also request WARC files.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Web crawling is managed through the Internet Archive's Archive-It service.
  This item is not a seed within an Archive-it collection, but capures of this page are found within:
  collection: University at Albany, SUNY Website
  created_date: 2012-09-17T13:15:00Z
  created_by: bkeough
  state: ACTIVE
  last_updated_date: 2016-09-26T23:38:05Z
  last_updated_by: system
  Web Collection
  - University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2009 September 12
    Scope and Contents
    Meta tag for keywords: Academics, SUNY, suny Albany, graduate degree programs, graduate programs, general education, international education, Why is general education so important, undergraduate education, Bachelor's degree programs, Master's degree programs, Academic Advising, curriculum
    Meta tag for description: Information about the University at Albany's majors & minors, nine schools & colleges, academic opportunities, the office of the provost as well as links to the academic calendar, schedule of classes and the course catalogs
    Meta tag for author: Sairam Chinnam
    This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.
  - University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2011 September 3
  - University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2012 March 29
  - University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2012 July 1
  - University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2012 August 8
  - University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2012 October 22
  - University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2012 December 1
  - University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2013 January 2
  - University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2013 February 1
  - University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2013 February 17
  - University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2013 April 1
  - University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2013 May 8
    This item had no crawl rules.
    The CDX index for this capture did not contain crawl information.
  - WARC file for University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2013 May 8
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Researchers interested in data analysis with web archives may request a WARC file. WARC files are very large and difficult to work with. Your request may take time to process, and we may be unable to deliver your request remotely. Please consult an archivist if you are interested in advanced research with web archives.
  - University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2013 September 1
  - University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2013 September 4
  - WARC file for University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2013 September 4
  - University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2013 October 1
  - University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2013 October 30
  - WARC file for University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2013 October 30
  - University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2014 August 27
  - WARC file for University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2014 August 27
  - University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2014 September 3
  - WARC file for University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2014 September 3
  - University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2014 September 10
  - WARC file for University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2014 September 10
  - University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2014 September 17
  - WARC file for University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2014 September 17
  - University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2015 February 4
  - WARC file for University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2015 February 4
  - University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2015 February 11
  - WARC file for University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2015 February 11
  - University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2015 July 17
    crawl: 165088
    Crawl Times
    start_date: 2015-07-17T16:55:07Z
    original_start_date: 2015-07-17T16:55:07Z
    last_resumption: None
    processing_end_date: 2015-07-22T22:02:18Z
    end_date: 2015-07-22T21:28:19Z
    elapsed_ms: 448383534
    Crawl Types
    type: MONTHLY
    recurrence_type: MONTHLY
    pdfs_only: False
    test: False
    Crawl Limits
    time_limit: 432000
    document_limit: None
    byte_limit: None
    crawl_stop_requested: None
    Crawl Results
    status: FINISHED_TIME_LIMIT
    discovered_count: 518483
    novel_count: 22064
    duplicate_count: 310947
    resumption_count: 0
    queued_count: 185472
    downloaded_count: 333011
    download_failures: 280
    warc_revisit_count: 310940
    warc_url_count: 332912
    total_data_in_kbs: 92321075
    duplicate_bytes: 89386949991
    warc_compressed_bytes: 975896456
    Crawl Technical Details
    doc_rate: 0.74
    kb_rate: 205.0
  - WARC file for University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2015 July 17
  - University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2015 September 17
    crawl: 173356
    start_date: 2015-09-17T16:57:20Z
    original_start_date: 2015-09-17T16:57:20Z
    processing_end_date: 2015-09-23T01:24:03Z
    end_date: 2015-09-23T00:16:53Z
    elapsed_ms: 458363239
    discovered_count: 367719
    novel_count: 26001
    duplicate_count: 206766
    queued_count: 134952
    downloaded_count: 232767
    download_failures: 237
    warc_revisit_count: 206761
    warc_url_count: 232678
    total_data_in_kbs: 101606587
    duplicate_bytes: 94029637527
    warc_compressed_bytes: 157865634
    doc_rate: 0.51
    kb_rate: 221.0
  - WARC file for University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2015 September 17
  - University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2015 November 17
    crawl: 183657
    start_date: 2015-11-17T17:41:09Z
    original_start_date: 2015-11-17T17:41:09Z
    processing_end_date: 2015-12-03T05:50:07Z
    end_date: 2015-11-30T19:18:26Z
    elapsed_ms: 432098049
    discovered_count: 415196
    novel_count: 17867
    duplicate_count: 229881
    queued_count: 167448
    downloaded_count: 247748
    download_failures: 242
    warc_revisit_count: 229876
    warc_url_count: 247648
    total_data_in_kbs: 61913750
    duplicate_bytes: 62091532709
    warc_compressed_bytes: 256259119
    doc_rate: 0.57
    kb_rate: 143.0
  - WARC file for University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2015 November 17
  - University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2015 December 17
    crawl: 187970
    start_date: 2015-12-17T16:55:04Z
    original_start_date: 2015-12-17T16:55:04Z
    processing_end_date: 2015-12-22T21:57:26Z
    end_date: 2015-12-22T21:40:44Z
    elapsed_ms: 449129872
    discovered_count: 304232
    novel_count: 13877
    duplicate_count: 191764
    queued_count: 98591
    downloaded_count: 205641
    download_failures: 234
    warc_revisit_count: 191759
    warc_url_count: 205547
    total_data_in_kbs: 60257781
    duplicate_bytes: 60588343215
    warc_compressed_bytes: 34726906
    doc_rate: 0.46
    kb_rate: 134.0
  - WARC file for University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2015 December 17
  - University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2016 March 17
    crawl: 201840
    Crawl Rules
    Ignore Robots.txt for www.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for www.alumni.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for www.ualbanysports.com (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for library.albany.edu (last updated 2017-05-19)
    Ignore Robots.txt for alumni.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for asrc.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for atmos.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for bioinformatics.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for cela.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for choose.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for cs.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for csda.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for imls.ctg.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for www.ctg.albany.edu (last updated 2017-05-19)
    Ignore Robots.txt for cwig.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for events.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for hr.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for ibl.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for illiad.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for liblogs.albany.edu (last updated 2017-05-19)
    Ignore Robots.txt for libguides.library.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for scholarsarchive.library.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for listserv.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for m.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for math.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for omega.math.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for mumford.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for nyjm.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for pdp.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for resnet.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for rit.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for cyberphysics.rit.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for rna.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for slsc.albany.edu (last updated 2017-05-19)
    Ignore Robots.txt for uaems.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for uapps.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for wiki.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    start_date: 2016-03-17T16:54:59Z
    original_start_date: 2016-03-17T16:54:59Z
    processing_end_date: 2016-03-22T18:02:10Z
    end_date: 2016-03-22T16:56:57Z
    elapsed_ms: 432107388
    discovered_count: 639552
    novel_count: 138564
    duplicate_count: 332568
    queued_count: 168420
    downloaded_count: 471132
    download_failures: 1411433
    warc_revisit_count: 332563
    warc_url_count: 471037
    total_data_in_kbs: 116820623
    duplicate_bytes: 113225737713
    warc_compressed_bytes: 765920585
    doc_rate: 1.09
    kb_rate: 270.0
  - WARC file for University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2016 March 17
  - University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2016 May 17
    crawl: 212937
    start_date: 2016-05-17T16:55:02Z
    original_start_date: 2016-05-17T16:55:02Z
    processing_end_date: 2016-05-24T10:38:52Z
    end_date: 2016-05-22T22:20:27Z
    elapsed_ms: 451503421
    discovered_count: 8685839
    novel_count: 568136
    duplicate_count: 1043240
    queued_count: 7074463
    downloaded_count: 1611376
    download_failures: 229
    warc_revisit_count: 1043205
    warc_url_count: 1611247
    total_data_in_kbs: 246906729
    duplicate_bytes: 230750229955
    warc_compressed_bytes: 2352496320
    doc_rate: 3.57
    kb_rate: 546.0
  - WARC file for University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2016 May 17
  - University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2016 September 17
    crawl: 236726
    Block host dev.library.albany.edu
    start_date: 2016-09-17T16:55:32Z
    original_start_date: 2016-09-17T16:55:32Z
    processing_end_date: 2016-09-22T19:45:41Z
    end_date: 2016-09-22T17:03:18Z
    elapsed_ms: 432208662
    discovered_count: 1414002
    novel_count: 188377
    duplicate_count: 898376
    queued_count: 327249
    downloaded_count: 1086753
    download_failures: 287
    warc_revisit_count: 898345
    warc_url_count: 1086634
    total_data_in_kbs: 205611728
    duplicate_bytes: 200652210118
    warc_compressed_bytes: 309191153
    doc_rate: 2.51
    kb_rate: 475.0
  - WARC file for University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2016 September 17
  - University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2016 October 17
    crawl: 243096
    start_date: 2016-10-17T16:56:12Z
    original_start_date: 2016-10-17T16:56:12Z
    processing_end_date: 2016-10-22T20:32:46Z
    end_date: 2016-10-22T17:07:30Z
    elapsed_ms: 432270469
    discovered_count: 1819420
    novel_count: 557303
    duplicate_count: 900445
    queued_count: 361672
    downloaded_count: 1457748
    download_failures: 296
    warc_revisit_count: 900407
    warc_url_count: 1457649
    total_data_in_kbs: 215568357
    duplicate_bytes: 201221539907
    warc_compressed_bytes: 1485925187
    doc_rate: 3.37
    kb_rate: 498.0
  - WARC file for University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2016 October 17
  - University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2016 December 17
    crawl: 255339
    start_date: 2016-12-17T16:54:59Z
    original_start_date: 2016-12-17T16:54:59Z
    processing_end_date: 2016-12-22T23:02:36Z
    end_date: 2016-12-22T17:39:38Z
    elapsed_ms: 434651176
    discovered_count: 5605147
    novel_count: 672626
    duplicate_count: 721586
    queued_count: 4210935
    downloaded_count: 1394212
    download_failures: 247
    warc_revisit_count: 721559
    warc_url_count: 1394095
    total_data_in_kbs: 173161585
    duplicate_bytes: 152072050167
    warc_compressed_bytes: 4226018506
    doc_rate: 3.21
    kb_rate: 398.0
  - WARC file for University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2016 December 17
  - University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2017 May 17
    crawl: 301465
    Host Rule Type C CONTAINS meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/search? (last updated 2017-05-11)
    start_date: 2017-05-17T16:55:17Z
    original_start_date: 2017-05-17T16:55:17Z
    processing_end_date: 2017-05-23T00:29:43Z
    end_date: 2017-05-22T21:46:25Z
    elapsed_ms: 449440076
    discovered_count: 2923335
    novel_count: 388249
    duplicate_count: 1238165
    queued_count: 1296921
    downloaded_count: 1626414
    download_failures: 336
    warc_revisit_count: 1238113
    warc_url_count: 1626286
    total_data_in_kbs: 265327774
    duplicate_bytes: 251274786133
    warc_compressed_bytes: 3306915146
    doc_rate: 3.62
    kb_rate: 590.0
  - WARC file for University at Albany - SUNY - Office of the Provost, 2017 May 17
- Bulletins, 1845 - 2017 May 17; 2; 11.75 cubic ft.; 65 captures
  - Catalog of the State Normal School published in the District School Journal of the State of New York, Sept 1845 (v1,6) p 104-108 (photocopy) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Register and Circular of the State Normal School for the Term Ending Sept 17,1846 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Register and Circular of the State Normal School for the Term Ending Sept 16,1847 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Register and Circular of the State Normal School for the Term Ending Sept 21, 1848 (photocopy) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Register and Circular of the State Normal School for the Term Ending Sept 27, 1849 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Register and Circular of the State Normal School for the Term Ending Oct 3, 1850 (photocopy) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Register and Circular of the State Normal School for the Term Ending July 31, 1851 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Register and Circular of the State Normal School for the Term Ending July 13, 1854 (photocopy) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Register and Circular of the State Normal School for the Term Ending July 14, 1859 (list of graduates), 1860 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Register and Circular of the State Normal School for Term Ending July 14, 1864 (unordered) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Catalogue of the Officers and Students of the State Normal School for Term Ending July 1, 1869 (photocopy), 1868-1869 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Catalogue of the Officers and Students of the State Normal Schoolfor Term Ending Jan 26,1870 (photocopy), 1869-1870 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Catalogue of the Graduates of the State Normal School Albany, N.Y. for the Twenty six years ending June 30, 1870 (photocopy, incomplete) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Catalogue of the Officers and Students of the State Normal School for Term Ending Jan 25, 1871 (photocopy), 1870-1871 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Catalogue of the Officers and Students of the State Normal School for Term Ending Jan 23, 1872 (photocopy), 1871-1872 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Catalogue of the Officers and Students of the State Normal School for Term ending Jan 27, 1874 (photocopy) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Catalogue of the Officers and Students of State Normal School for Term Ending Jan 26, 1875 (photocopy), 1874-1875 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Catalogue of the Officers and Students of State Normal School for Term Ending Jan 25, 1876 (photocopy) (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Catalogue of the Officers and Students of the State Normal School for Term Ending Jan 25, 1881 (photocopy), 1880 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Catalogue of the Officers and Students of the State Normal School for Term Ending Jan 27, 1882 (photocopy) (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Catalogue of the Graduates of the State Normal School Albany, N.Y., For Thirty- Eight Years ending June 23, 1882 (photocopy) (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Announcement for the Term Commencing Feb 14, 1883 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Catalogue of the Officers and Students of the State Normal School for Term Ending Jan 26, 1883 (2 copies) (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Catalogue of the Officers and Students of the State Normal School for Term Ending Jan 25, 1884 (2 copies), 1883 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Officers, Faculty, and Graduates and Announcement for Term Commencing Sept 10, 1884 (2 copies) (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Officers, Faculty, and Graduates and Announcement for Term Commencing Sept 9, 1885 (incomplete copy supplemented by photocopies) (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Officers, Faculty, and Graduates and Announcement for Term Commencing Sept 14, 1887 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Officers, Faculty, and Graduates and Announcement for Term Commencing Feb 9, 1887 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Officers, Faculty, and Students and Announcement for Term Commencing Feb 8, 1888 (6 copies, some incomplete) (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Officers and Faculty and Announcement for the Term Commencing Feb 13, 1889 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Officers and Faculty and Announcement for the Term Commencing Sept 11,1889 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Circular of the New York State Normal College for 1890 and 1891 (cover page only) (Box 1, Folder 32)
    Only the cover of the pamphlet is present.
  - Circular of the New York State Normal College for 1891 and 1892 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    Item missing.
  - Circular of the New York State Normal College for 1892 and 1893 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Circular of the New York State Normal College for 1894 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Circular for the New York State Normal College for 1896 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Circular of the New York State Normal College for 1898, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Circular of the New York State Normal College for 1899 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Circular of the New York State Normal College for 1901 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Catalogues, 1903-1904 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Catalogue, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Catalogue, 1905 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Catalogue, 1906-1907 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Catalogue, 1907-1908 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Catalogue, 1908-1909 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Catalogue, 1909-1910 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Catalogue, 1910-1911 (Box 2, Folder 4)